Mike Smith

Smyrna, GA, 30082

Phone: 770.851.0497 | Email: mike@mikeqsmith.com

Website: www.mikeqsmith.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/mikeqsmith

GitHub: https://github.com/mqsmith

Summary

A Full Stack Web Developer with certification from the Georgia Institute of Technology and Harvard University. Experienced professional leader with a 10-year background in live event production and a life-long dedication to continuous learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known among teammates for collaboration and strong attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, java, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, ReactJS.

Applications: Microsoft Office Suite, Google Suite, Final Cut Pro, Photoshop, After Effects, Illustrator, InDesign, Keynote, Pro Presenter, Pro Video Sync, Pro Video Player

Projects

Slap Bet | www.mikeqsmith.com/slapbet | https://github.com/mqsmith/slapBet

Description: A friendly betting app that allowed even the most novice bettor to make educated wagers on their favourite teams

Technologies used: D3, Chart.js, Formspree, Firebase, ajax, Bootstrap, jQuery

Bananas 2 Bananas | http://banana2banana.herokuapp.com/ |

https://github.com/mgsmith/banans2bananas

Description: Allows the user to compare products a different stores to find the cheapest price. Technologies used: MySQL, NodeJS, HTML, MaterializeCSS, JavaScript, jQuery Dependencies include: sequelize, express, path, doteny, nodemon, mysql2

Virtulogics | https://virtulogics.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/mqsmith/virtulogics Description: VMware capacity planning simplified. This application takes a clean, simple, straightforward look into your environment to keep you N+.

Technologies used: Mongo, NodeJS, Express, React, JavaScript, Influx, telegraf, Bootstrap, jwt Dependencies include: mongoose, express, path, dotenv, nodemon, redux, jwt, bcrypt

Experience

Passion Productions 2015 to 2019 Technical Director

Led all production aspects, e.g., technology, gear, and team leadership, for the Cumberland location and enterprise events including implementing the vision and culture of Passion City Church within the production team. Ensured internal and external client satisfaction by building

relationships, gaining trust and requesting feedback. Launched a new location and set the groundwork for future teams to step into. Cultivated a consistent rotation of volunteers through leadership and motivation, solving a year-long issue for the company. Successfully managed a yearly budget of \$900,000

Technical Coordinator

Led multiple teams of production contractors to execute events with audio, lighting, video and performances by managing pre-planning calls, gear rental, and other event preparation.

Freelance Live Event Production

2009 to 2015

Production Technician

Served as Producer, Programming Director, Lighting Director and Lighting Designer. Scheduled and trained volunteer teams on proper implementation and storage of production equipment. Managed and archived all production data.

AE Production Services 2011 to 2012

Production Technician

Served as Lighting Designer, Audio Director, Stage Manager, Inventory and Gear Specialist, and Technician for various music festivals with artists including: Dierks Bentley, Edwin McCain, Daughtry, Luke Bryan, Atlanta Party Band, David Nail, and Parmalee.

Education

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate: Georgia Institute of Technology

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Introductory Computer Science Certificate: HarvardX of Harvard University

A 11-week program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Objective-C, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Python & MySQL..

Bachelor of Arts, Sports Business: University of Georgia

Completed 100/120 hours